uncommongoods.com 2019-05-11

# Privacy Policy | UncommonGoods

UncommonGoods, LLC (“UncommonGoods”) respects your privacy and wants you to understand our privacy policy. This Privacy Policy page communicates how, when, and why we gather information about our customers and what we do with it.

UncommonGoods reserves the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time. By accessing www.UncommonGoods.com (“Website”), you confirm that you have read and understand this policy including how and why we use your information. If you don’t want us to collect or use your personal information, you should not use the Website or order goods from UncommonGoods. We are not responsible for the content or privacy policies of third parties.

All persons accessing the Website or using UncommonGoods services must be at least 18 years of age. Minors under 18 and at least 13 years of age may access the Website only if they have appropriate permission and direct supervision by the owner of the account. Children under age 13 are not permitted to use the Website. You are responsible for any and all account activity conducted by a minor on your account.

**Website Security**

We have taken many precautions to protect confidential information while you shop using the UncommonGoods Website. We use the industry-standard SSL protocol (Secure Sockets Layer) to secure credit card transactions. The SSL system encrypts information that you submit to us via our website when you place an order as a safeguard against third party interception of your information. 

**IP Address**

To facilitate a smooth shopping experience, our system logs the Internet Protocol (IP) Address of each user. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer every time you browse the internet. Depending on your Internet Service Provider (ISP) and the type of connection, this number may change each time you log on. Information from IP addresses is used for system administration, our live help feature, troubleshooting, and the examination of traffic trends and response rates to various promotional offers. 

**Gathering and Use of Your Personally Identifiable Information**

If you place an order through UncommonGoods, we will ask you for your name, email address, shipping address, telephone number and credit card information. You may provide other information in custom orders you make such as the names of a member of a family, the family name, the year the family was established, and locations they lived. We use this information to process and fulfill your order and to notify you of your order status. Telephone numbers and e-mail addresses are used to contact you regarding your order. Alternatively, you may request to receive our e-mail newsletter updates.

If you purchase from us, UncommonGoods may opt your mailing and purchase info into a cooperative marketing database used by other companies that may want to market goods or services to you. UncommonGoods does not receive direct monetary compensation for participating in this cooperative and you can opt out at any time by emailing [privacy@uncommongoods.com](mailto:privacy@uncommongoods.com).

We collect information from you when you visit our site including your IP address or unique device identifier, and cookies and data from the pages you visit. To learn more about our use of cookies, visit https://www.uncommongoods.com/static/privacy.jsp#cookies-policy. This is stored in log files and used to provide you more pertinent content when you visit our site. Your IP address, when available is used to provide a localized experience including prices in your currency and to adhere to regional preferences and requirements.

We use your personal information to improve and customize our services, including sharing of your information for such purposes. This includes uses which we intend to provide an optimal match between you and our available products and services, including direct marketing. Such uses serve our interest in improving and growing our business and your interest in receiving optimal user results.

We use your personal information for security and safety purposes, including our own use and with third party security providers. We aim to protect you and us from spam, harassment, intellectual property infringement, crime and other security risks. We use personal information to comply with legal obligations pursuant to the legal protections afforded to you in your country. Where required to obey the law, such as in response to a subpoena or legal process we will disclose your personal information. We also reserve the right to use your personal information to exercise or defend legal claims.

We use your personal information to engage third party companies and individuals to provide services to us (such as payment processors, research companies, and analytics and security providers) to help us operate, provide and market our products and services. We use third parties where necessary or where their services are superior to what we could perform internally.

We will only retain your information for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this policy or as needed to provide services to you or to advertise or market services to you. For example, we may not delete your personal information insofar as it is needed to uphold our legal obligations, resolve disputes, or enforce our agreements.

If you would like to modify your information on file with us, request deletion of data, or terminate your account, please contact [privacy@uncommongoods.com](mailto:privacy@uncommongoods.com)

**Email List**

When you sign up for our email newsletters, we ask for your first name and email address. If you do not wish to receive our email anymore, an unsubscribe button is located at the bottom of each email for your convenience. You can also unsubscribe by contacting [Privacy@uncommongoods.com](mailto:privacy@uncommongoods.com).

**Catalog Mailings**

Anyone who purchases from us or [signs up](http://www.uncommongoods.com/catalogSignup/catalogSignup.jsp) could receive a catalog from us.

We may make portions of our mailing list available to carefully selected companies. This includes customer names, addresses, and purchase details. Consequently, if you sign up to receive our catalog or make a purchase with us, you may receive other catalogs whose products or services might interest you.

If you do not want to receive a catalog from UncommonGoods, please email [remove@uncommongoods.com](mailto:remove@uncommongoods.com)

with your name, address, and the blue code from your catalog's back cover. If you do not want to receive catalogs from other carefully selected companies, please ask to be added to our Do Not Share list by emailing your name and address to [donotshare@uncommongoods.com](mailto:donotshare@uncommongoods.com).

**_Online Tracking_**

Website uses Google Analytics and may be able to see user’s referring site. Website does not respond to “do not track” signals, though users may be able to provide tracking instructions to Google Analytics. To opt out of Google Analytics, visit the Google Analytics opt-out page found at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout and install the add-on for your browser. For more details on installing and uninstalling the add-on, please see the relevant help resources for your specific browser. 

**_GDPR Compliance_**

UncommonGoods complies with the requirements of the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) with respect to data concerning citizens or residents of European Union countries and Switzerland. To the extent other terms of this Privacy Policy or UncommonGoods Terms and Conditions contradict the terms herein as applied to EU Residents and Citizens, the terms of this “GDPR Compliance” section control.

EU residents and citizens have the following eight rights under GDPR and are entitled to the facilitation of these rights by UncommonGoods as set forth herein:

**Right to be Informed.** UncommonGoods collects the following “personal information” as defined in GDPR when a sale is consummated: name, e-mail address, shipping address, telephone number and credit card information. You may provide other information in custom orders you make such as the names of a member of a family, the family name, the year the family was established, and locations they lived. We use this information to process and fulfill your order and to notify you of your order status. You may also choose to provide us with your personal information of varied nature if you contact us regarding customer service concerns.

**Right of Access.** EU residents and citizens have a right to be informed of data that is stored, processed or analyzed and to obtain a copy in plain English. To request such information please email us at [Privacy@uncommongoods.com](mailto:privacy@uncommongoods.com) using the same email you used to complete your transaction and provide us with your payment information in order to provide your account security.

**Right to Rectification.** EU residents and citizens have a right to revise our information if inaccurate or complete, and if information is disclosed to third parties to have that information rectified by the third parties. If after accessing your information, an EU resident or citizen believes our information on file regarding you is inaccurate, one may respond to the email which was provided with information pursuant to EU resident or citizen right of access and provide the rectifying information.

**Right of Erasure.** This is a non-absolute ‘right to be forgotten.’ If you are an EU resident or citizen and after accessing your information you would like to have it erased, please send an email explaining the circumstances warranting erasure to the email which provided your information pursuant to your right of access. We may comply with the request, we may have a legal obligation to preserve some or all data under relevant laws, and/or we may have a legal right to retain information you have requested be deleted. You will be advised of our decision regarding your data erasure request.

**Right to Portability of Data.** EU residents and citizens have a right to have your data stored with us to be moved, copied or transported in a safe and secure manner without affecting its usability. If you would like your personal data in portable form, please email a request to [Privacy@uncommongoods.com](mailto:privacy@uncommongoods.com) with the subject line “REQUEST FOR PORTABLE DATA.”

**Right to Object to Processing.** EU subjects may object to direct marketing including including any personalized website content, emails, or to all processing of their personal information. EU citizens and residents have an absolute right to object to use of their personal data for direct marketing purposes. You may not have an absolute right to object if your personal data is used for a task carried out in the public interest, or for legitimate interests such as scientific or historical research or statistical purposes. If you are an EU citizen or resident who objects to processing of their personal information, please send an email request to [Privacy@uncommongoods.com](mailto:privacy@uncommongoods.com) with the subject line “OBJECTION TO PROCESSING” and tell us whether you object to direct marketing or all processing.

**Rights in Relation to Automated Decision-making.** UncommonGoods uses personal information to profile customers including to facilitate direct marketing. UncommonGoods may also provide emails, marketing, or advertising to EU citizens or subjects by automated means, and automated (non-human) responses to customer actions or requests. If you would like more information regarding UncommonGoods automated decision-making or to request human follow up to an automated promotion or UncommonGoods’ communication, or a response to an EU citizen or resident action or request, please send an email request to [Privacy@uncommongoods.com](mailto:privacy@uncommongoods.com) with the subject line “AUTOMATED DECISIONMAKING” and provide the details of the transaction in question.

**Privacy Policy Changes.** We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we believe the changes are material, we will let you know by one or more of the following: (1) posting a conspicuous notice on the Website or (2) sending you an email regarding the changes.

This privacy policy is published and takes effect May 25, 2018

UncommonGoods would like you to know more about the web technologies that we use to run our web shop. These technologies are meant to provide as many people with the best browse and purchase experience possible, and provide advertising, site-experience, and other benefits to this end. You can read about this in further detail in this policy document.

In this privacy policy, we’ll refer to UncommonGoods.com and UncommonGoods LLC collectively as the “Site”. We’ll refer to cookies and related technologies collectively as “Cookie Technologies.”

## Types of Cookie Technologies

**Cookies**

Cookies are small data files sent from a server to your web browser. They are stored in your browser’s cache and allow a website or a third party to recognize your browser. There are three primary types of cookies:

  * _Session cookies_ are specific to a particular visit and carry information as you view different pages so you don’t have to re-enter information every time you change pages or attempt to checkout. Session cookies expire and delete themselves automatically in a short period of time like after you leave the Site or when you close your web browser.
  * _Persistent cookies_ remember certain information about your preferences for viewing the site, and allow UncommonGoods to recognize you each time you return. Persistent cookies are stored on your browser cache or mobile device until you choose to delete them, and otherwise typically delete themselves at expiration.
  * _Third-party cookies_ are placed by a party other than UncommonGoods, and may gather browsing activity across multiple websites and across multiple sessions. They are usually a type of persistent cookie and are stored until you delete them or they expire based on the time period set in each third-party cookie. Most notably, third-party cookies allow third-party server to show you items that you’ve shown interest in, either directly or indirectly.

Cookies store data about your use, but they are helpful because they allow us to help UncommonGoods function and customize your experience.

**Other Technologies**

In addition to cookies, there are other similar technologies used by UncommonGoods and elsewhere on the web or in mobile ecosystems.

  * _Web pixels:_ These are tiny graphics (sometimes called “clear GIFs” or “web beacons”) with a unique identifier that are used to understand browsing activity. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, web beacons are rendered invisibly on web pages when you open a page.
  * _Social widgets:_ These are buttons or icons provided by third-party social media providers that allow you to interact with those social media services when you view a web page or a mobile app screen. These social widgets may collect browsing data, which may be received by the third party 
  * _UTM codes:_ These are strings that can appear in a URL (the “Uniform Resource Locator,” which is typically the http or https address entered to go to a web page) when a user moves from one web page or website to another, where the string can represent information about browsing, such as which advertisement, page, or publisher sent the user to the receiving website.

UncommonGoods uses Cookie Technologies to recognize your logged-in state on UncommonGoods.com, to understand what purchases members and visitors are interested in, to make UncommonGoods Sites function for you, and to help your browsing experience and use of the Site feel more customized. More generally, UncommonGoods uses Cookie Technologies for the following.

**Security and Authentication (Strictly Necessary)**

Some cookie and similar technology functions are necessary and vital to ensuring that UncommonGoods works properly for visitors and members, such as maintaining the security, safety, and integrity of the Site, authentication and logging into UncommonGoods (including remembering permissions and consents you have granted), and ensuring the ability to securely complete transactions.

**Account and User Preferences**

Some technologies are used to remember your account and preferences over time, such as remembering your account or keeping yourself logged in when returning to UncommonGoods, maintaining your choices on UncommonGoods features and how you want UncommonGoods to appear and customizing content based on how you use UncommonGoods.

**Social Networks**

Some technologies help you to interact with social networks you are signed into while using the Services, such as sharing content with the social network and other features you employ with the social network, or that are allowed in the social network’s privacy policy. These may be set and controlled by the social networks, and your preferences with those social networks.

Social networks may also work with UncommonGoods or with you for analytics or for marketing purposes, as discussed below. You may be able to manage your privacy preferences for these social networks and their tools and widgets via your account with the social network.

**Performance and Analytics**

Some technologies help provide performance data on how the Services are functioning in order to improve UncommonGoods and the Services, including, for example, data on site and app functionality and speed to help us optimize UncommonGoods, how the Services are used to help us improve your experience on UncommonGoods, and detecting and gathering reporting on bugs to help make UncommonGoods work better.

The Site also employs Google Analytics to help understand how UncommonGoods is used by its community. For some of the advertising features listed below, like retargeting, data from Google Analytics may be combined with UncommonGoods first-party data and third-party cookies (like Google’s advertising cookies). To see how to opt-out of Google Analytics Advertising Features, see the Opt-Out section at the bottom of this policy.

You can find more information on how Google Analytics works in this [Google guide.](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage)

**Marketing Services**

UncommonGoods partners with third-party service providers that may use various Cookie Technologies to permit us and them to learn about what ads you see and click when you visit UncommonGoods, the Apps, and affiliated sites or to show you ads on and off UncommonGoods. These may include things such as:

  * _Frequency capping_ , which limits the number of times a user’s browser or mobile device displays the same ad;
  * _Attribution tracking_ , which estimates what advertising or marketing source brought someone to UncommonGoods, or determines what marketing source led to actions like a visit or a purchase;
  * _Remarketing_ , which shows relevant ads to an audience based on prior shopping and browsing patterns on UncommonGoods;
  * _Audience targeting_ , which refers to targeting advertisements to a large audience based on the audience’s known or inferred demographics;
  * _Cross-device recognition_ , which recognizes actions across multiple devices or browsers.

Some third-party service providers may provide information like demographics, cross-device information, or interest categories from a combination of sources that, while not identifying you personally, permit us to provide you with more relevant and useful advertising. In some cases, this information may have non-marketing performance analytics uses as well.

These technologies allow a partner to recognize your computer or mobile device each time you visit UncommonGoods or other websites and mobile applications based on data like a cookie, your IP address, or device ID, but do not allow access to other personal information from UncommonGoods. However, these technologies may allow us or a third party to recognize you, either from a single device or across devices, over time. These third parties are required to follow applicable laws, self-regulatory programs, and UncommonGoods data protection rules where applicable. However, UncommonGoods does not have control over these third parties, who each have their own privacy policies and privacy practices.

**Consent, Contract, and Legitimate Interests in Processing**

Certain Cookie Technologies are employed to make the Site function for its intended purpose, and are provided based on contractual necessity based on your agreement with UncommonGoods to perform the services you have requested.

By choosing to use our Services after having been notified of our use of Cookie Technologies in the ways described in this Policy, and, in applicable jurisdictions, through notice and unambiguous acknowledgement of your consent, you agree to such use.

**Opt-in and Opt-out on Browsers**

In addition, when you use UncommonGoods via a browser, you can change your web browser’s settings to reflect your cookie preferences for cookies directly from the site you are on or for third-party cookies. Each browser is a little different, but usually these settings are under the “options” or “preferences” menu. The links below provide information about cookie settings for the browsers supported by UncommonGoods:

**Opt-out of Third-Party Networks**

If you do not wish to have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based advertisements, you may decline to receive interest based ads through if you are located in the European Union by clicking [here](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note this does not stop you from being served advertisements. You will continue to receive generic advertisements. Please note that if you reject or block all cookies in your browser settings, you will not be able to take advantage of UncommonGoods Services as some cookies are necessary for the Site to function properly.

You can learn more about managing your preferences for ads online, particularly for many third-party advertising networks, through resources made available by the Digital Advertising Alliance at [https://www.aboutads.info](https://www.aboutads.info/) or the Network Advertising Initiative at [https://optout.networkadvertising.org.](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/)

**Google Analytics Opt-out**

For Google Analytics Advertising Features, you can [opt-out](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en) through [Google Ads Settings](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated), Ad Settings for mobile apps, or any other available means (for example, the NAI's consumer opt-out listed above). Google also provides a Google Analytics [opt-out plug-in](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) for the web.

**Criteo Opt-out**

For Criteo, which primarily serves ads based on products you’ve interacted with, you can opt out [here](https://www.criteo.com/privacy/) at any time. The opt-out page also contains detailed information on how this works and how to ensure your Criteo settings persist.

**Third-Party Tools**

Various third parties provide browser plug-ins and apps that can help provide you information on, and limit or block, third-party cookies, web beacons, and some Javascript-based technologies. UncommonGoods cannot vouch for the efficacy of a particular third-party product, but popular products that provide these privacy enhancements include [Ghostery](https://www.ghostery.com/) and [AdBlock Plus](https://adblockplus.org/).

**Contact Us**

If you have questions about the use of Cookie Technologies at UncommonGoods, or if you would like to make changes to the way your data is being used, please email UncommonGoods [Privacy Policy team](mailto:privacy@uncommongoods.com).
